<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on chs.us</title>
    <link>//localhost:60471/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on chs.us</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 22:36:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:60471/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Is Appsec Fyi</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/what-is-appsec-fyi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 22:36:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/what-is-appsec-fyi/</guid>
      <description>AppSec.fyi is your ultimate guide to all things related to application security (AppSec). In today&amp;rsquo;s digital landscape, where cyber threats are increasingly sophisticated, protecting your applications from vulnerabilities is paramount. This platform serves as a comprehensive resource for developers, security professionals, and anyone interested in securing software applications.&#xA;At its core, AppSec.fyi provides valuable insights, best practices, and the latest trends in application security. From articles discussing common vulnerabilities like SQL injection and cross-site scripting to tutorials on secure coding practices and tools, the platform covers a wide range of topics essential for building robust and secure applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Python&#39;s New Subinterpreters</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/exploring-python-subinterpreters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/exploring-python-subinterpreters/</guid>
      <description>Exploring Python&amp;rsquo;s New Subinterpreters&#xA;The Python community never ceases to innovate. One of the most recent additions to Python&amp;rsquo;s vast feature set is &amp;ldquo;subinterpreters&amp;rdquo;. As the name suggests, subinterpreters provide a way to run multiple isolated Python interpreters within a single process. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive deeper into this novel concept and discuss its advantages and potential use cases.&#xA;What are Subinterpreters?&#xA;At a high level, each subinterpreter in Python has its own distinct memory space and execution state.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turtle Cove Snorkeling</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/turtle-cove-snorkeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 09:16:20 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/turtle-cove-snorkeling/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 PostMessage Security: Protecting Cross-Origin Communication</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/html5-postmessage-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/html5-postmessage-security/</guid>
      <description>HTML5 introduced a powerful feature called postMessage that allows secure communication between different origins or domains. While this functionality provides a convenient way to exchange data across frames or windows, it also poses potential security risks if not implemented correctly. In this article, we will explore the security considerations of using postMessage and discuss best practices to protect cross-origin communication.&#xA;Understanding postMessage postMessage is an HTML5 feature that enables asynchronous communication between different browsing contexts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is GitHub CoPilot?</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/what-is-github-copilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/what-is-github-copilot/</guid>
      <description>GitHub Copilot is an AI-powered coding assistant developed by GitHub in collaboration with OpenAI. It uses machine learning algorithms to assist developers in writing code by suggesting code snippets based on the context of the code being written. This powerful tool has the ability to autocomplete code, provide inline documentation, and generate entire functions, making coding easier and more efficient.&#xA;GitHub Copilot is built on top of OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s GPT-3 language model, which has been trained on a vast amount of data from a variety of sources, including code repositories, documentation, and programming languages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Basic Burp Extension in Python</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/burp-extension-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 09:16:20 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/burp-extension-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Burp Suite is a popular web security testing tool that helps you secure web applications by testing and validating vulnerabilities. It’s a comprehensive platform for performing security assessments on web applications, and its extensibility is one of its key features.&#xA;Burp Suite extensions are add-ons that allow you to customize and extend the functionality of Burp Suite. These extensions can be written in any JVM-compatible language, including Java, Python, and Ruby.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Context Managers in Python</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/python-context-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 09:16:20 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/python-context-managers/</guid>
      <description>Python is a powerful and versatile programming language that offers many features to help developers write clean and efficient code. One of these features is the use of context managers. In this blog post, we will take a closer look at what context managers are and how they can be used to simplify and improve your Python code.&#xA;A context manager is an object that defines the methods enter() and exit().</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Content Security Policy (CSP)</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/csp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 09:16:20 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/csp/</guid>
      <description>Content Security Policy (CSP) is a security measure that helps protect web applications from various attacks, including Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) and data injection. CSP works by specifying a set of Content Security Rules that dictate what resources are allowed to load on a page. This can be used to whitelist trusted sources of content, or to block untrusted content entirely.&#xA;One advantage of Content Security Policy is that it can help to prevent malicious code from running on a page.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Burp Extension in Ruby Part 1</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/burp_plugin_ruby_part_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 14:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/burp_plugin_ruby_part_1/</guid>
      <description>Writing a Burp Extension in Ruby Burp extensions can be written in 3 languages - Java, Python, and Ruby. Since Burp is a java app, in order to write extensions in Python you need Jython and in Ruby you need JRuby. For this example, we&amp;rsquo;ll use Ruby.&#xA;Step 1 - Downloading JRuby The first step is to download JRuby from https://jruby.org/download.&#xA;For this example we will be using the latest - 9.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passive Search Burp Extension</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/passive-search-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 15:06:39 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/passive-search-extension/</guid>
      <description>Introducing my latest Burp extension - &amp;ldquo;Passive Search&amp;rdquo;. Passive Search searches for a list of terms in HTTP responses and creates an issue if it finds one.&#xA;I got the idea of after maintaining a list of things that I was checking for in responses and using either the search in HTTP History on an item by item basis or using the global Search. It was a completely manual process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Project!</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/new-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 06:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/new-project/</guid>
      <description>Today I started a new project that I’ve been thinking about for awhile. It’s located at – https://appsec.fyi. It is a growing collection of interesting links that I’ve found regarding varying application security topics. The basic site is up and the plumbing is there. Just need to add more content. Check it out!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python List Comprehensions</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/python-list-comprehensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 06:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/python-list-comprehensions/</guid>
      <description>Python List Comprehensions is a pretty interesting feature that I haven’t seen in other languages (at least that I’ve played with). The basic idea is that they create lists from other iterables. They consists of brackets containing the expression which is executed against each item in the iterable object. One or more conditionals dictate if the item is added to the new list.&#xA;The basic format is –&#xA;list = [expression for_loop_one_or_more conditions]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AuthHeader Updater listed on snoopysecurity/awesome-burp-extensions</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/authheader-updater-listed-on-snoopysecurity-awesome-burp-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 01:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/authheader-updater-listed-on-snoopysecurity-awesome-burp-extensions/</guid>
      <description>Excited to see AuthHeader Updater on a list of awesome burp extensions!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auth Header Updater Released!</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/auth-header-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 03:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/auth-header-update/</guid>
      <description>Excited to release Auth Header Updater today – a Burp extension to update Authorization headers during a scan and also guest post about it on ihackthings.online.&#xA;Read more about it at ihackthings.online or chs.us.&#xA;Source code and plugin available on GitHub. ~</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New version of jekyll-clicky!</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/new-version-of-jekyll-clicky/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 04:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/new-version-of-jekyll-clicky/</guid>
      <description>I’ve updated jekyll-clicky to version 0.1.3. This fixes an issue where some posts weren’t getting the javascript code and changed it to be asynchronous..&#xA;Check it out at RubyGems and find the source at Github.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Burp Extension – Perfmon</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/new-burp-extension-perfmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 04:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/new-burp-extension-perfmon/</guid>
      <description>Just whipped together a new Burp extension called perfmon (not to be confused with the Windows tool of the same name). I was really interested in the the resource usage of Burp while doing certain activities.&#xA;It adds a new tab to Burp and samples every 5 seconds-&#xA;Current and max number of threads in use&#xA;Current and max memory used&#xA;Current and max memory allocated&#xA;Ticker to set how often the stats update.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Burp Extension – Part One</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/writing-a-burp-extension-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 04:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/writing-a-burp-extension-part-one/</guid>
      <description>This is the first part in a series that I plan to write on how to create Burp extensions. I became interested in writing Burp extensions at a previous company where we were fortunate enough to be given time to do research presentations and then present them to our peers. My first presentation topic was to write an Active Scanning extension in Burp that would look for XXE (XML External Entity Injection).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BinPeek – an app to determine if a #Windows executable is managed or unmanaged.</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/binpeek-an-app-to-determine-if-a-windows-executable-is-managed-or-unmanaged/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 02:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/binpeek-an-app-to-determine-if-a-windows-executable-is-managed-or-unmanaged/</guid>
      <description>BinPeek is an application that checks to see if a Windows application is managed(.NET) or unmanaged(native). It handles x86 and x84 executables. If doing it manually, you must check several values in the PE (Portable Executable) file header that differ slightly based on whether the executable is 32-bit or 64-bit. BinPeek does that work for you.&#xA;Usage&#xA;Project Page on Github&#xA;Install&#xA;Build with Visual Studio or just use the release version in the repo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure Design Principles</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/secure-design-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 02:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/secure-design-principles/</guid>
      <description>Sitting here on a cold, snowy day thinking about secure design principles. These are key to think about during the design phase of a feature/project?&#xA;Total Mediation – every access to every resource must be validated every time&#xA;Economy of Mechanism – keep it as simple as possible&#xA;Fail-Safe – in case of failure, default to a secure state&#xA;Defense in Depth – layer security&#xA;Open Design – the security of a system should not be dependent on secrecy of its design or implementation</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Gems Updated</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/gemsupdated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 02:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/gemsupdated/</guid>
      <description>PwnedCheck&#xA;PwnedCheck is a gem that checks http://haveibeenpwned.com to see if an email address or user handle has been involved in a breach.&#xA;How to Install&#xA;How to Use&#xA;Jekyll-Clicky&#xA;Jekyll-clicky is a gem to add clicky analytics to a site generated with Jekyll.&#xA;Installation&#xA;Add this line to your application’s Gemfile:&#xA;And then execute:&#xA;Or install it yourself as:&#xA;### Usage Add-&#xA;to _config.yml in your jekyll site directory. Replace ### with the id of your clicky site.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extending Burp at DerbyCon VII</title>
      <link>//localhost:60471/blog/extendingburptalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 03:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:60471/blog/extendingburptalk/</guid>
      <description>Just finished my talk about extending Burp at Derbycon VII. Thanks to everyone that attended! I’m really thankful for the opportunity to present on the topic.&#xA;The Details-&#xA;Slides –&#xA;Video in Slides (Slide 14)&#xA;Source Code – https://github.com/sampsonc/searchplusplus&#xA;Video of the Presentation&#xA;I’d love to hear any comments/questions.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
