<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on chs.us</title><link>/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on chs.us</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exploring Python's New Subinterpreters</title><link>/blog/exploring-python-subinterpreters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/exploring-python-subinterpreters/</guid><description>Exploring Python&amp;rsquo;s New Subinterpreters
The Python community never ceases to innovate. One of the most recent additions to Python&amp;rsquo;s vast feature set is &amp;ldquo;subinterpreters&amp;rdquo;. As the name suggests, subinterpreters provide a way to run multiple isolated Python interpreters within a single process. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive deeper into this novel concept and discuss its advantages and potential use cases.
What are Subinterpreters?
At a high level, each subinterpreter in Python has its own distinct memory space and execution state.</description></item><item><title>Writing a Basic Burp Extension in Python</title><link>/blog/burp-extension-in-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 09:16:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/burp-extension-in-python/</guid><description>Burp Suite is a popular web security testing tool that helps you secure web applications by testing and validating vulnerabilities. It’s a comprehensive platform for performing security assessments on web applications, and its extensibility is one of its key features.
Burp Suite extensions are add-ons that allow you to customize and extend the functionality of Burp Suite. These extensions can be written in any JVM-compatible language, including Java, Python, and Ruby.</description></item><item><title>Context Managers in Python</title><link>/blog/python-context-managers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 09:16:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/python-context-managers/</guid><description>Python is a powerful and versatile programming language that offers many features to help developers write clean and efficient code. One of these features is the use of context managers. In this blog post, we will take a closer look at what context managers are and how they can be used to simplify and improve your Python code.
A context manager is an object that defines the methods enter() and exit().</description></item><item><title>Python List Comprehensions</title><link>/blog/python-list-comprehensions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 06:25:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/python-list-comprehensions/</guid><description>Python List Comprehensions is a pretty interesting feature that I haven’t seen in other languages (at least that I’ve played with). The basic idea is that they create lists from other iterables. They consists of brackets containing the expression which is executed against each item in the iterable object. One or more conditionals dictate if the item is added to the new list.
The basic format is –
list = [expression for_loop_one_or_more conditions]</description></item></channel></rss>